A Guide to the Dorothy I. Parker papers FA417
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1938-1985; 1
  - Assignments: Asia, Indian Agricultural Program (IAP), 1.5
    - Publications - Final Report, 1969; 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 54)
      Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR) Institutes and Agricultural University Libraries.
    - Publication - Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR), 1960 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      "Indian Journal of Agricultural and Veterinary Education" (includes Parker article)
      - Publication - Politics, International Relations, and Law, 1965
        separated to RAC Library
      - Publication - Sorghum, IAP Bibliography, 1973
    - Resume, Parker - Assignment in India, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Assignments: Asia, International Rice Research Institute (IRRI), 1.6
    - Bibliography - Cropping Systems, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Bibliography - Cropping Systems, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Bibliography - Cropping Systems, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Bibliography - Cropping Systems, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Bibliography - Cropping Systems, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Bibliography of Translations for IRRI Bibliography, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Cumulative Indexes - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1971-1975 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Publication - "Primer on Growing Rice", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Publications, 1960-1976 (Box 11, Folder 64)
      Bylaws, bibliography, program brochure. "The IRRI Monographs" by Parker.
    - Summary of Planning for IRRI Library, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 71)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 72)
    - Supplement - International Bibliography of Rice Research, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 73)
    - Theses and Dissertations on Rice Available in the Library of IRRI, 1974-1979 (Box 14, Folder 74)
    - Travel Itinerary, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 75)
  - Assignments: Asia, Other Libraries, 1.7
    - Japan - Keio University Correspondence and Reprint, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 76)
    - Japan - Keio University Review of Library School, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 77)
    - Japan - Keio University Review of Library School, 1972; Copy 2. (Box 14, Folder 78)
    - Japan - Keio University Review of Library School, 1972; Copy 3. (Box 14, Folder 79)
    - Japan - Keio University Review of Library School, 1972; Copy 4. (Box 14, Folder 80)
    - Thailand - Kasetsart University Publications (Box 14, Folder 81)
    - Thailand - Kasetsart University Library Plans and Correspondence, Bangkhen Campus, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 82)
    - Thailand - Kasetsart University Library Plans, Kamphaengsaen Campus, 1974; 2 copies. (Box 15, Folder 83)
    - University of Philippines, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 84)
  - Library Programs: Other, 1.8
    - Africa - Library Development (Box 15, Folder 85)
      memoranda, reports, reprints.
    - Africa - National Council for Research, Agricultural Research Council Bibliography, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - Agricultural Program - Publication, Parker and Carabelli, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 87)
      "Guide for an Agricultural Library Survey for Developing Countries"
    - Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT), Colombia - Publications, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 88)
      - "Simposio sobre el Potencial del Tropico Bajo"
      - "Catalogo de Publicaciones Periodicas de la Biblioteca del CIAT", 2 copies.
      - Senior Staff of CIAT
    - Colombia - Universidad del Valle, 1969-1974 (Box 15, Folder 89)
      Correspondence and seminar papers
    - Correspondence - Pan American Union, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 90)
    - Correspondence - Pan American Union, 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 91)
    - Library Development - Speeches, Drafts, and Papers by Parker, 1960-1974 (Box 16, Folder 92)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1976; 1979 (Box 16, Folder 93)
      "Cooperation Canada" and "Agricolas"
    - Travels, 1958-1966 (Box 16, Folder 94)
    - University Library Development (Box 16, Folder 95)
      Reports, reprinted resources, and planning summaries
  - Post-Retirement: Cotton Project, 1.9
    - Article and Supplement -"Boll Weevil Losses", 1974 (Box 16, Folder 96)
    - Consultant Resources - Textile Information Organizations and Research (Box 16, Folder 97)
    - Consultant Work and Travels, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 98)
      Meeting notes, diaries, correspondence, and participant organization information.
    - Draft Report, J. G. Harrar, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 99)
      "An Expanded Research and Development Programme for Cotton".
    - Economic Outlooks - National Cotton Council of America Reports, 1958-1965 (Box 17, Folder 100)
    - Economic Outlooks - National Cotton Council of America Reports, 1967-1974 (Box 17, Folder 101)
    - Essays, Articles, Manual, and Reports, 1940-1975 (Box 17, Folder 102)
      - "Handbook for Cotton Classers"
      - "Cotton Programs of the Federal Government: 1929-1967"
      - "Cottonseed Protein - Problems and Opportunities"
      - "Potential of Cottonseed: Products, Composition, and Use"
      - "Liquid Cyclone Process for Edible Cottonseed Flour Production"
      - "Upland Cotton"
      - "The Energy Crisis: Can Cotton Help Meet It?"
      - "Mid-Season Foreign Trade Report"
      - "World Trends in Man-Made Fibers"
      - "Economic Forces in the 1974-1975 Cotton Outlook"
    - International Institute for Cotton and the Cotton Board, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 103)
      Publications, press releases, and annual report
    - Publications and Pamphlets - Shirley Institute and Hollings College (Box 17, Folder 104)
    - Publications - National Cotton Council of America and CIBA-GEIGY (Box 18, Folder 105)
    - Publications - Research Institutes, London (Box 18, Folder 106)
      Reports, guides, and brochures. The Textile Institute, The Textile Council, Cotton Research Corporation, The Textile Statistics Bureau.
    - Publications - "World Textile Abstracts", 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 107)
    - Reprints, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 108)
    - United Nations Development Programme - Reports, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 109)
    - United Nations Development Programme - Reports, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 110)
    - United Nations Industrial Development Organization - Meeting Papers, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 111)
  - Post-Retirement: Other, 1.10
    - Agricultural Sciences Seminar - Working Papers, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 112)
    - International Development Research Center (IDRC), Canada - Publications, 1970-1973 (Box 19, Folder 113)
      Brochures, reports, and speech
    - International Development Research Center (IDRC) - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 114)
    - International Development Research Center (IDRC) - Publications, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 115)
      - "Research Policy: Eleven Issues"
      - "The First 100 Projects"
      - Annual Report
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA) - Conference, 1975 January (Box 19, Folder 116)
      Arranged by author.
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA) - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 117)
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA) - Ibadan Library, 1968-1975 (Box 19, Folder 118)
      Correspondence and publications.
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Ibadan Library - Bibliography, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      "A Bibliography of Yams and the Genus Dioscorea"
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Ibadan Library - Union List, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 120)
    - Manual - Economics Training, CIMMYT, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 121)
    - Manual - Wheat Production, Turkey (Box 20, Folder 122)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Programs: Other, 1.11
    - International Agricultural Development Service (IADS) - Publications and Newsletters, 1978-1981 (Box 20, Folder 123)
    - International Agricultural Development Service (IADS) - Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 124)
    - International Agricultural Development Service (IADS) - Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 125)
    - International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) ? Bibliography, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 126)
    - International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) - Publications, 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 127)
    - Program for the Support of Dance, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 128)
- U.S. Government Departments and Programs, 1962-1981; 2
  Series 2 is arranged into three subseries:
  Subseries 1, Department of Agriculture, consists of publications from the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA). Most of the material is published by the National Agricultural Library as well as the Associates of the National Agricultural Library, a part of the USDA that received a Rockefeller Foundation grant in 1972. The documents range from 1962 to 1981.
  Subseries 2, Department of State: Agency for International Development (AID), contains material from Parker's post-retirement consultant work with the agency. In particular, Parker was a consultant for the AID Library Panel through the National Science Foundation. Included in this subseries are publications from conferences, grantees, and research projects. Multiple bibliographies are included in this subseries, focusing on such topics as crops, land use, and urban development, among others. The materials span from 1968 to 1979.
  Subseries 3, Other, contains miscellaneous government-related publications and program information, ranging from 1963 to 1971.
  - Department of Agriculture, 2.1
    - Associates of National Agricultural Library Newsletters, 1971-1975 (Box 21, Folder 129)
    - Associates of National Agricultural Library Newsletters, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 130)
    - Associates of National Agricultural Library Newsletters, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 131)
    - Associates of National Agricultural Library Newsletters, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 132)
    - Associates of National Agricultural Library - Miscellaneous Papers, 1971-1975 (Box 22, Folder 133)
      Correspondence, press releases, meeting minutes, report, and membership information.
    - National Agricultural Library (NAL) - Newsletters, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 134)
    - National Agricultural Library (NAL) - Newsletters, 1977-1979 (Box 22, Folder 135)
    - National Agricultural Library (NAL) - Newsletters, 1979-1981 (Box 22, Folder 136)
    - National Agricultural Library Publication - Collection Development Policy, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 137)
    - Publications, 1962-1975 (Box 22, Folder 138)
      "Reading for Soil Scientists, Together with a Library"; "Composition of Foods...Raw, Processed, Prepared".
  - Department of State: Agency for International Development (AID), 2.2
    - AID Workshops - Research Information Networking, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 139)
      Correspondence, drafts, and workshop papers
    - Bibliographies, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 140)
      - "Community Water Supply"
      - "Malaria Eradication"
      - "Wheat Production Programs"
      - "Rice Production Programs"
      - "Poultry Development Programs"
      - "Development Assistance to Schools and Institutes of Administration in Developing Countries"
      - "Administrative Reform"
      - "Systems Approaches to Technical Cooperation: The Role of Development Administration"
      - "Urban Development, Including Housing"
      - "Land Reform"
    - Bibliographies, 1970-1972 (Box 23, Folder 141)
      - "Popular Participation in Development: Title IX"
      - "Administration of Agricultural Development"
      - "Book, Textbook and Library Development"
      - "Fisheries"
      - "Advisors and Counterparts: Relationships between Foreign Technical Assistance Experts and Host Country Colleagues"
    - Bibliographies, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 142)
      - "Agricultural Credit and Rural Savings"
      - "Social Indicators"
      - "Teacher Education"
    - Bibliography Series - Memoranda, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 143)
    - Consortium for International Development (CID) - Information Network Workshop, 1975 September (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - Grants, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Grants - Directory, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 146)
      "A Directory of Institutional Resources Supported by Section 211(d) Grants"
    - National Science Foundation, AID Library Panel - Consultant Work, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Publications, 1968-1974 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Publications - Grantees, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - Publications - Utah State University, Grantee, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 150)
    - Publications - Research Abstracts, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 151)
    - Publication - Research Catalog, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 152)
    - Publications - Research Reports, 1973; 1979 (Box 25, Folder 153)
    - Sorghum Information Management Network Workshop, 1975 May 12-13 (Box 25, Folder 154)
    - Sorghum Network Conference, Puerto Rico, 1975 January (Box 25, Folder 155)
    - Sorghum Workshop Publication, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 156)
  - Other, 2.3
    - Government Advisory Committee on International Book and Library Programs, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 157)
    - Public Health Monograph, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 158)
- United Nations, 1974-1975; 3
  Includes publications from U.N. agricultural and international development programs.
  - International Agricultural Program - Publication, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 159)
    U.N. Agricultural Development Program
  - Tropical Products Institute, Vol. 1, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 160)
  - Tropical Products Institute, Vol. 2, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 161)
  - Tropical Products Institute, Vol. 3, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 162)
- Friends and Colleagues, 1950-1979; 4
  Consists of publications and ephemera from various friends and colleagues. Also included is correspondence which does not relate to Rockefeller Foundation work.
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1961-1974 (Box 27, Folder 163)
    Correspondents include but not necessarily limited to: Metcalf, Keyes; Munn, Robert F. Dr., University of West Virginia Library; Weaver, Warren.
  - Memorial and Commemorative Programs, 1964-1979 (Box 27, Folder 164)
    - Publication - "The Winds of Freedom", Dean Rusk, 1963
  - Ralph Shaw - American University Publications, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 165)
  - Ralph Shaw - Correspondence and Ephemera, 1957-1972 (Box 27, Folder 166)
    Includes correspondence with Robert Munn.
  - Reprints, 1950-1967 (Box 27, Folder 167)
- Professional Organizations, 1955-1981; 5
  Subseries 1, Asociacion Interamericana de Bibliotecarios y Documentalistas Agricolas (AIBDA), includes newsletters and other materials from 1969-1981. Parker was an honorary member of the AIBDA.
  Subseries 2, Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas (IICA), contains publications and newsletters from 1970-1977.
  Subseries 3, International Association of Agricultural Librarians and Documentalists (IAALD), consists of newsletters and other publications from 1959-1980. Parker was a member of the executive committee of the IAALD.
  Subseries 4, Other, includes materials from miscellaneous organizations with which Dorothy Parker was connected during her lifetime. These include the Agricultural History Society, American Association of University Women, American Library Association, Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America, Inc., and the Association of Agricultural Librarians and Documentalists in India (AALDI). The papers from the American Association of University Women include biographical information on Parker. The materials range from 1955 to 1973.
  Series 5 is arranged into four subseries:
  Subseries 1: Asociacion Interamericana de Bibliotecarios y Documentalistas Agricolas (AIBDA); Subseries 2: Instituto Interamericano de Ci.encias Agricolas (IICA); Subseries 3: International Association of Agricultural Librarians and Documentalists (IAALD); Subseries 4: Other.
  - Asociacion Interamericana de Bibliotecarios y Documentalistas Agricolas (AIBDA), 5.1
    - Bibliographies of Agriculture, 1971-1973 (Box 27, Folder 168)
    - Newsletters, 1972-1975 (Box 27, Folder 169)
    - Newsletters, 1976-1981 (Box 28, Folder 170)
    - Newsletters - Information Sciences, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 171)
    - Proceedings - AIBDA Conference, 1972; hardback book. (Box 28)
    - Special Bulletins, 1971-1975 (Box 28, Folder 172)
    - Special Bulletins, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 173)
    - Technical Bulletins, 1969-1976 (Box 28, Folder 174)
      Parker compiled/edited 1969 issue
    - Technical Bulletins, 1976-1979 (Box 29, Folder 175)
  - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas (IICA), 5.2
    - Agriculture Bibliography Bulletins and Newsletters, 1970-1974 (Box 29, Folder 176)
      Vol. 7, No. 3 is dedicated to Parker.
    - Publication - Agricultural Index, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 177)
      "Indice Agricola de America Latina y el Caribe"
    - Publication - Agricultural Index, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 178)
    - Publications - Inter-American Information System for the Agricultural Sciences (Agrinter), 1973-1977 (Box 29, Folder 179)
  - International Association of Agricultural Librarians and Documentalists (IAALD), 5.3
    - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 29, Folder 180)
    - Publications, 1960-1967 (Box 29, Folder 181)
      - "World Directory of Agricultural Libraries and Documentation Centres"
      - "Primer for Agricultural Libraries", Parker
        -
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1959-1964 (Box 30, Folder 182)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 183)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 184)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 185)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 186)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 187)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1972-1976 (Box 31, Folder 188)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1977-1979 (Box 31, Folder 189)
    - Quarterly Bulletins, 1979-1980 (Box 31, Folder 190)
  - Other, 5.4
    - Publications and Member Information, 1955-1973 (Box 31, Folder 191)
      - American Association of University Women
        Includes biographical information and list of Parker publications.
      - Middle Atlantic Chapter of the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America, Inc.
      - Agricultural History Society
      - Association of Agricultural Librarians and Documentalists of India (AAIDL)
      - American Library Association
- Miscellaneous/Ephemera, 1932-1978; 6
  Contains materials which have no apparent connection to any specific program or organization listed previously. This subseries includes publications and reports which mostly relate to agriculture and libraries. They may have been resources for her work. This series also contains reprints from Parker's early career, prior to her work with the Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Computerized Information Sources - University of Arizona (Box 32, Folder 192)
  - Manchester Public Libraries, 1963-1975 (Box 32, Folder 193)
  - Publications by Parker, 1932-1945 (Box 32, Folder 194)
    - "General Distribution of the Species of Aster Found in Indiana"
    - "Affinities of the Flora of Indiana: Part I"
    - "The Hepaticae of Indiana"
    - Book Reviews
  - Publications - Miscellaneous, 1962-1978 (Box 32, Folder 195)
    - "The Chancellor's Lecture: Universities under Siege"
    - "American Philanthropic Foundations"
    - Graduation Address at the University of Ibadan
    - "Two Revolutions"
    - "Fertilizer Abstracts"
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden Newsletter
    - "Television, the Book, and the Classroom: A National Seminar"
  - Publication - "Statistical Methods in Agricultural Research", 1972 (Box 32, Folder 196)
    - Publication - The Strawberry: Bibliography, 1969
  - Report by Rockefeller University - Peking Union Medical College, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 197)